本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
等等
Wait.
斯坦叔公
Grunkle Stan!
孩子们  真是难以置信
Kids! I can't believe it!
我以为我失去你们俩了
I thought I lost you two.
派恩斯先生  真的是你
Ahh! Mr. Pines, it's really you!
为了这个拥抱的瞬间  我已经拿陌生人练习好多次了
I've been hugging strangers to practice for this moment.
我们好想你  你个怪老头儿
We missed you, you old codger.
我也想你们这些小笨蛋
I've missed you knuckleheads too.
你们能回来真好
It's good to have you back.
那么  大家都在这儿干嘛呢
So... what's everyone doing here?
对啊  这里有  怪物和小矮人
Yeah, there's, like, monsters and gnomes.
那是穿着土豆麻袋的帕西菲卡吗
And is Pacifica wearing a potato sack?
就算穿麻袋我还是比你好看
Hey! Even in a sack I still look better than you.
这  说来话长
It's... It's a long story.
有没有人给我点吃的
Hey, is anyone gonna feed me?
拉里・金的蜡像头想要点零食
Larry King's disembodied wax head wants num-nums.
我们食物有配额的  还记得吗
We're trying to ration our food, remember?
又来了
Uhh, it's happening again!
嘿  各位
Hey, everyone!
眼球蝙蝠
Eye bat!
躲避模式
Evasive maneuvers!
-嘘  别说话  -把灯灭了
- Shh! Keep it down! - Get the lights!
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
■
时间轴： WaitinZ  leland
翻译： Peace  战忽局副局座  乔乔央央  小小妖音箬  leland  Wizard小希
■
校订： Enpistu  WaitinZ
后期： leland  Enpistu
怪诞小镇  第二季第二十集
Gravity Falls  S02E20  Weirdmageddon 3: Take Back The Falls
欢迎来到幸存的正常人聚集地
Welcome to what's left of normal around here...
大本营
Home base.
我们有  多处受伤
We have... Several injuries
噢  我的肝疼
Ooh! Ow! My liver, girl!
朗博・麦克斯克尔米什
Rumble McSkirmish?
别害怕
Do not be afraid.
湮灭之日已经让我明白
Weirdmageddon has taught me
有些战斗我赢不了
there are some battles I cannot win.
我现在是谦逊・麦克斯克尔米什
I am now Humble McSkirmish.
绝 望 值
斯坦叔公  这到底是怎么回事
Grunkle Stan, how'd this all happen?
当时我正在门外挂招牌
So I was hammering signs out back
天空开始吐出梦魇
when the sky started vomiting nightmares.
我总听收音机广播
I listen to a lot of AM radio,
所以知道这是怎么回事  世界末日
so I knew what this meant... The end of the world.
但接下来发生的事我可没料到
<i>What I didn't expect was what happened next.</i>
看来你和我兄弟对小屋施的法
<i>Turns out whatever you and my brother did to the Shack</i>
独角兽巫术什么的
<i>with your unicorn voodoo</i>
让外面的怪诞无法侵入这里
<i>made the crazy place invincible to weirdness.</i>
对啊  独角兽咒语
Of course... The unicorn spell!
所以只有这地方能在比尔的魔法中幸免于难
That's why this is the only place Bill's magic can't touch.
然后我闻到了一股负鼠味儿
That's when Possum Breath over here shows up
一群受伤的流浪者穿过树林出现了
leading a bunch of injured stragglers through the forest.
他们需要容身的地方
They needed a place to stay,
而且由于现在镇长被抓走了
and since the Mayor got captured,
我推举自己为代理镇长
I elected myself de facto chief.
计划是住在这里吃煎肉罐头直到弹尽粮绝
The plan's to stay in here and eat brown meat until we run out.
然后我提议吃小矮人
Then I vote we eat the gnomes.
嘿  我只是矮  还没聋呢
Hey, I'm short, not deaf!
嘘  压力太大你会嚼不烂的
Shh! Shh! Stress will make you chewy.
斯坦叔公  我们不能就这么躲在小屋里
Grunkle Stan, we can't all just hide inside the Shack.
整个小镇需要我们拯救
There's a town in need of saving!
我和阿福叔公本想救大家  但他被比尔抓走了
Me and Ford tried to do it, but he got captured by Bill.
真是自作自受
Serves that jerk right!
我兄弟总是想出些愚蠢的计划
My brother's had some stupid plans,
要和全宇宙最强大的恶魔作对更是蠢到家了
but going up against an all-powerful space demon was his worst one yet.
相信我  这里有我们需要的一切
Trust me, we have everything we need right here.
虽然不是豪华旅馆  但至少怪物们会按摩
It's not the Ritz, but at least the monsters inside know how to massage.
-你会指压按摩吗  -会  我上过课
- You know Shiatsu? - Yes, I've taken some classes.
你真的准备让比尔得逞吗
So, you're really just gonna let Bill win?
孩子  我们这里很安全
Look, kiddo. We got a good deal here.
而且  我很确定无论其他镇民在哪里
Besides, I'm sure wherever the rest of the townsfolk are,
他们都很安全
they're fine.
■
王座之灾!
这里是珊多拉・西梅内斯
This is Shandra Jimenez
在比尔的城堡为大家带来现场报道
reporting live from the inside of Bill's castle.
首次曝光
Here for the first time
被抓镇民下落的图像
are images of what's happened to the captured townsfolk.
如果不想目睹自己的朋友转变为
Viewers are advised to look away
由人类的痛苦组成的狰狞王座
if they don't want to see their friends
建议观众谨慎观看
turned into a twisted throne of human agony.
-妈妈爸爸  -我的家人
- Mom and Dad? - My family!
杜兰德副警长
Deputy Durland!
没人能够拯救这座小镇的人民了吗
Is there no one who will save the people of this town?
我是珊多拉・西梅内斯  正被飞行的眼球变成石头
I'm Shandra Jimenez, and I'm being turned into stone by a flying eyeball.
噢不  虽然我爸妈不是好人
Oh, no. My parents are bad,
但即便如此  也不该把他们变成石头呀
but even <i>they</i> don't deserve to be turned to stone.
我恨你  比尔
Curse you, Bill!
你为什么要带走我们所爱的一切
Why must you take everything we love?
各位  还不明白吗  我们的朋友需要我们
Guys, don't you see? Our friends need us,
但只有奋起反击  才能救他们
but we only save them if we fight back!
梅宝说得对  比尔就盼着我们躲起来
Mabel is right. Bill wants us to run and hide.
他希望我们认为他是无敌的
He wants us to think he's invincible.
但阿福叔公在被抓前告诉我
But Ford told me before he was captured
他知道比尔的秘密弱点
that he knows Bill's secret weakness.
弱点
Weakness?
现在  如果我们团结一心
Now, if we band together,
如果我们联合所有人的力量
if we combine all of our strength,
所有人的智慧
our smarts,
还有  托比的随便什么
our... whatever Toby has...
黄金疱疹
<i>Aureus</i> rashes!
那我们就有可能救出阿福
Then we just might be able to rescue Ford,
找到比尔的弱点
learn Bill's weakness,
拯救重力泉
and save Gravity Falls!
你们是不是都忘了这里谁说了算
Have you all forgotten who's in charge here?
况且  我们只有在屋里才安全
Besides, we're only safe inside!
我们又不能把神秘小屋搬去比尔那里
It's not like we can take the Mystery Shack to Bill.
我勒个天  煎饼班卓琴在上啊
Holy hootenanny! Flapjack and fiddlebanjos!
抱歉  抱歉  有点激动
Sorry. Sorry. Got a little excited.
我是想说
What I meant to say is,
我想到一个击败比尔救出阿福的办法
I think I figured out a way to fight Bill and rescue Ford.
但这需要集体的力量
But we're all gonna have to work together!
现在
Now...
如果我们
if you just...
别担心  阿福  我们来救你了
Don't worry, Ford. We're coming for you!
放我走  你这个三角形的疯子
Let me go! You insane three-sided...
这  这里是什么地方
Wha... What is this place?
我们将重逢
<i>We'll meet again</i>
不知何地  不知何时
<i>Don't know where, don't know when</i>
噢  我们将在阳光灿烂的日子重逢
<i>Oh, I know we'll meet again some sunny day</i>
我  我在哪儿
Wh... Where am I?
你在楼顶套房  小子
<i>You're in the penthouse suite, kid!</i>
金字塔的塔尖  喝一杯吧
<i>The tip of the pyramid! Have a drink.</i>
不要拘束
<i>Make yourself comfortable.</i>
你知道那个沙发是由活人的皮肤做的吗
<i>You know that couch is made from living human skin?</i>
别耍花招了  赛弗
Quit the games, Cipher!
既然我还活着  那你一定是有求于我
If I'm still alive, you must want something from me.
啊  还是那么聪明  小福福
<i>Ah, sharp as ever, Fordsy.</i>
你可能也注意到了
<i>As you may have noticed...</i>
我最近进行了多维度的改造
<i>I've recently had a multi-dimensional makeover!</i>
我可以控制空间和物质
<i>I control space and matter,</i>
现在没有那个大傻孩碍手碍脚
<i>and now that that dumb baby's out of the way,</i>
时间也归我掌管了
<i>time itself!</i>
但我也不是一直有这种能力
<i>But I wasn't always this way.</i>
你觉得这些锁链很紧吗
<i>You think those chains are tight?</i>
想象一下活在二维空间的样子
<i>Imagine living in the second dimension...</i>
扁平的思维在扁平的世界做着扁平的梦
<i>Flat minds in a flat world with flat dreams.</i>
我解放了我的维度  斯坦福  我现在来解放你的
<i>I liberated my dimension, Stanford, and I'm here to liberate yours.</i>
现在只有一个障碍  我发现
<i>There's just one hitch. As it turns out,</i>
我的怪诞无法跑出这座小镇的魔力限制
<i>my weirdness can't escape the magical confines of this town!</i>
有什么东西把我困在这里了
<i>There's something keeping me in.</i>
难以置信  重力泉的怪诞磁学自然法则
Incredible! Gravity Falls' Natural Law of Weirdness Magnetism.
我多年前研究过
I studied this years ago!
-那你知道怎么消除这个法则吗  -当然
- And did you find a way to undo it? - Of course!
用一个简单的等式就能把防护罩摧毁
There's a simple equation that could collapse the barrier.
但我就是死也不告诉你
But I'd never tell you!
听好  阿福  只要你把等式告诉我
Listen, Ford, if you just tell me that equation,
你们的时空就自由了
finally your dimension will be free!
一切将皆有可能
Anything will be possible!
我会重建一个好玩的世界  更美好的世界
I'll remake a fun world- a better world!
一场永不散会的宴席  和一位永不消亡的主人
A party that never ends with a host that never dies!
再也没有条条框框
No more restrictions!
没有任何法则
No more laws!
你会成为我们的一员
You'd be one of us.
全知全能
All-powerful!
比你能想象的任何事物都要强大
Greater than anything you've imagined!
我就只需要你的帮助了
And all I need is your help.
你以为我会帮你  别做梦了
You're insane if you think I'll help you.
梦是无论如何都会做的  老天才
Ha ha ha! I'm insane either way, brainiac!
合不合作随你
But have it your way.
我只要随便搜搜  就能把等式直接
I'll just fish around and get that equation
从你脑子里掏出来
directly out of your mind!
先别着急
Not so fast!
比尔  规矩你都懂
You know the rules, Bill.
在我梦里搅局对你来说不难
You may be able to haunt my dreams,
但是除非与我握手获得准许
but you can't enter my mind
否则你是无法进入我的思维的
unless I shake your hand and let you in.
看来你把简单问题复杂化了
You're making this so much harder than it needs to be.
硬骨头  每个人都有软肋
Everyone has a weakness, tough guy!
我会撬开你的嘴
I'll make you talk!
只是需要一点时间罢了
It's only a matter of time.
好嘞  老子想当年也是搞了不少幺蛾子发明
All right. I've made some thingamadiculous robomajigs in my day,
这还是第一个不会被用上邪路的
but this is the first one that won't be used for evil!
哇  这些蓝图太了不起了  麦戈科特
Whoa! These blueprints are incredible, McGucket.
这是你迄今最叹为观止的发明了
This is your most amazing invention yet.
我有问题  这上边装枪剑了么
Question. Does it have any gun-swords?
日漫我看得多了
I watch a lot of anime and, uh,
相信我吧  现在什么都得装枪剑
trust me, you're gonna want some gun-swords.
日漫是什么
What's an "Anime"?
-这我们可有的聊了  -没什么好聊的
- We have much to discuss. - Discuss, nothing!
这些鬼画符全是忽悠人的狗屁
These scribbles are a bunch of cockamamie balderdash!
抱歉  不该用法语骂人
Excuse my French.
你那才不是法语
再说了  你上哪儿找
And where would you even
那么多二傻子来建造这玩意呢
find a bunch of idiots crazy enough to build it?
斯坦叔公  你面前不就是一帮二傻子么
Grunkle Stan, you're lookin' at those idiots.
都是二傻子
Idiots!
重力泉垃圾场
货真价实的垃圾堆
哎哎  你干啥呢这是
Whoa... What... What are you...
喂喂喂  说你呢  别乱碰
Hey... Hey, now. Hey! Don't touch that.
夺回重力泉
梅宝  谢谢你送的末日款毛衣
Thanks for these apocalypse sweaters, Mabel.
世界毁灭之日还能穿得这么舒服
The end of the world has never been so comfortable.
好吧  我穿还不行吗
Uhh! Fine, I'll wear it.
但我是不可能喜欢这种款式的
But I'm not gonna like it.
承认吧  现在就是世界末日前最美好的一天
Admit it. This is the best day of the end of the world.
而且我们真的有机会击败比尔
I think we actually have a chance to beat Bill
赢回我们的未来
and win back our future.
对啊  活着见到我们的
Yeah. Getting to actually live
十三岁生日聚会
to see our 13th birthday party
就是我现在唯一想要的生日礼物
is the only birthday present I want right now.
嘿  如果我们都能活到那天
Hey, if we're lucky enough to get there,
我保证全镇的居民会为你们
I guarantee this whole town is gonna throw you
开一场有史以来最棒的生日聚会
the best birthday party you've ever seen.
谢谢了  苏斯
Thanks, Soos.
哎  有人看见斯坦叔公了吗
Hey, has anyone seen Grunkle Stan?
整个计划也太扯淡了
This whole plan is bonkers.
压根没人咨询代理镇长的意见
But of course, no one asked the Chief what he thinks.
我都为大家奉献那么多了
After all I've done for everyone!
史麦布莱克
Schmebulock.
说得好  这简直就是一坨史麦布莱克
Yeah, exactly... it's a total load of schmebulock.
斯坦叔公  没出什么事吧
Is something wrong, Grunkle Stan?
你好像比平时更爱生闷气了
You're acting grunklier than usual.
还不是因为这个救我兄弟的计划
It's this darn plan to save my brother.
目标：
救出     阿福！
给你们提个醒  是我把他从传送门那端救回来
If you didn't notice, I already saved him once from that portal,
他却连个谢字也没说
and he never thanked me!
世界末日是他引发的
He causes the end of the world,
怎么还满街都还是
and somehow it's still always
“斯坦搞砸  阿福救世”的调调
"Stan's the screw-up, Ford's the hero."
大家认为他是英雄
Well, maybe people think he's a hero
还不是因为他没待在小屋子里当缩头乌龟
because he didn't want to hide in the Mystery Shack!
说不定他躲在神秘小屋里
Well, maybe if he hid in the
就不会被逮走了
Mystery Shack he wouldn't have been captured!
各位  各位  相信我  明天一定大获全胜
Guys! Guys! Trust me, tomorrow's gonna be great!
-我相信所有人的能力  -救命啊  梅宝领袖
- I believe in us. - Help! Leader Mabel!
我总是不小心在毛衣里秀肌肉
I keep accidentally flexing through my sweater!
看吧  又来了
Aah! It happened again!
这几只牛魔王还真讨喜
Those weird cow-monsters are delightful!
来啦
Coming!
各位瞧好了
All right, fellas!
希望这个发明比我其他的都有用
Let's hope this turns out better than my other inventions!
大家准备好了吗
Everybody ready?
迪普  就是现在
Dipper, now!
原谅我吧  孩子  你这套易燃商品
Forgive me, boy. Your hyper-flammable merchandise
是我唯一的依靠了
is the only thing keeping me goin'.
我勒个地狱火啊
What in blazes?!
快住手  住手啊
No! No! Nooo!
打算开口了吗
Ready to talk now?
决不
I won't.
我是不会放你进入我的思想的
I won't let you into my mind!
大家觉得咋样啊  再给他加五百伏特
What do you think, pals? Another 500 volts?
哎  这是什么声音
Hey, do you hear that?
什么  我才刚把门修好
What?! I just fixed that door!
伙计  见识见识小屋斗士的厉害吧
It's the Shacktron, dude!
他们把房子改装成机器人了
They made the house into a robot.
真了不起
Fascinating!
看来你们这群肉体凡胎想反击啊
So the mortals are trying to fight back, huh?
好可爱
Adorable!
超时空罪犯  不用说你们也知道
Henchmaniacs, you know what to do!
把他们灭了
Take them out!
这下可完蛋了
This was a bad idea.
各位伙计们  能听到我说话不
Uh, hey, dudes. Is this thing on?
试音
Tes...
怪兽哥们儿姐们儿  我只有一事相求
Heh. Uh, I just wanted you monster dudes
把阿福交出来  不然我们恐怕就得  打架的干活
to hand over Ford, or we'll have to, like, fight and junk?
哟  你挺可爱的嘛
Heh heh. Hey, you're a little cutie.
我在数不清的卫星上屠宰了百万生灵
I have butchered millions on countless moons!
妈呀  我还是喜欢你说话前的样子
Whoa. I liked you better before you talked.
这家伙真刻薄
Real... real bring-down, this guy.
进攻
Attack!
伙计们  可以了
All right, dudes!
各就各位  按计划行动
Everyone! Like we planned!
三  二  一  上
Three, two, one. Go!
好猪猪
Ha ha ha! Good pig.
湖怪  快把他们拿下
Get 'em, Gobblewonker!
你想得美
Oh, no, you don't!
各位  来袭警报
Everyone! Incoming!
难道连个逃生舱都没有吗
Does this thing have an escape hatch?
各位  最大功率运行
Everybody! Maximum power!
就是现在
And... now!
不会在逗我吧
Guys, seriously?
你们连这一件事都做不好
You had, like, one job to do here.
迪普  梅宝  干得好
Bravo, Dipper and Mabel!
哟  我可是知道了
Well, would ya look at that?
那些孩子是真的很关心你
<i>Those kids really care about you.</i>
你也很关心他们
<i>And you care about them.</i>
对吧
<i>Don't you?</i>
你想干什么  哦不
What are you... Oh. Oh, no.
或许折磨这些孩子能让你开口
<i>Perhaps torturing those kids will make you talk!</i>
不不不  别动他们  你不许
No. No! Not the kids! You ca...
我们来做个了断
<i>Lets get this over with.</i>
怎么回事  不
<i>What the... No!</i>
不不不不不
<i>No! No! No! No!</i>
攻击
Attack!
啊  我的眼睛
<i>Aah! My eye!</i>
你们知道
<i>Do you have any idea</i>
再生一只眼睛需要多长时间吗
<i>how long it takes to regenerate that?</i>
他分心了  这是我们的机会
We've got him distracted! Now's our chance!
救援小队  出发
Rescue team, move out!
好了  大伙儿
OK, everyone!
我们进去  救出阿福叔公
We get in, rescue Ford,
出来  拯救世界
get out, save the world.
就是这么简单
Piece of cake.
我们先明确一下
Just so we're clear,
如果我死了  我要控告你们所有人
if I die, I'm suing all of you.
嘿  我们再考虑一下
Hey, on second thought,
也许能想个新计划
maybe we could come up with a plan
一个不需要我们去送死的计划
that doesn't involve us plummeting to our certain death.
出发
Now!
哦  天哪  哦  天哪
Oh, man, oh, man...
天哪  离近看更恐怖了
Oh, man. It looks even worse up close.
我找到阿福叔公了
I found Great-uncle Ford!
他金光闪闪  但看起来并不好
He's golden! But not in the good way!
太好了  带上他  然后我们离开这里
Great. Grab him and let's get out of here.
可是我们怎么解救这些石化的人
But how are we going to unfreeze them?
我知道
I know!
吉迪恩  你这是怎么了
Gideon! What happened to you?
比尔抓住了我  他逼我
Bill captured me. He's been forcing me
在这个小笼子里跳可爱的舞  直到永远
to do cute dances in this cage for all eternity.
我受够了一直装可爱
I'm so tired of being cute!
那我们怎么才能解开魔咒呢
How do we undo this?
泰勒镇长  他是承重的那个人
Mayor Tyler. He's the load-bearing human.
把他拉出来  整个结构就会倒塌
Pull him out, and the whole thing goes down.
我嘴里有噩梦的味道
Ah. My mouth tastes like nightmares!
现在我的黑暗和扭曲可不是无病呻吟了
Aah! I think I'm dark and tortured for <i>reals</i> now.
这次经历将成为有点・神叨叨心中永远的阴影
This experience will forever scar Tad Strange.
再也不穿水手服了
No more sailor suits!
-温蒂  -大伙儿
- Wendy! - Guys!
妈妈  爸爸
Mom! Dad!
杜兰德
Durland!
布拉布斯
Blubs!
再也不要这样吓我了
Don't you <i>ever</i> scare me like that again!
孩子们  你们成功了
Kids! Ah, you did it!
我就知道你们俩靠得住
I knew I could count on you two. Ha ha!
费多福  我
Fiddleford, I...
自从我们那次分道扬镳之后就再也没有见过
I haven't seen you since we parted ways.
你一定很恨我
You must hate me.
我以前总想忘记这一切
I've tried forgettin'.
但或许我应该试着原谅
Maybe I should try <i>forgiving.</i>
过来  我的老朋友
Come here, old friend.
兄弟  见到你我也很高兴
Hey, good to see you too, bro.
但我们还是先离开这里吧
Now let's get out of here, huh?
听着  阿福叔公  时间不多了
Listen, Uncle Ford, we don't have a lot of time.
你还记得石化之前是怎么跟我说的吗
Remember how you told me right before you were frozen
你说你知道比尔的弱点
that you knew Bill's weakness?
对  有个能打败他的秘密方法
Yeah, a secret way to defeat him?
我是知道
I... I do!
你们有人带钢笔了吗  铅笔  什么都行
Now, does anyone have a pen? Pencil? Anything?
这就行了
Perfect!
呃  我们在外面拖着比尔
Uh, we've got Bill outside,
但是我也不知道我们还能拖多久
but I don't know how long we can keep him occupied.
好的好的  很好很好
Yes, yes. Good, good.
在地板上画个圈圈
Drawing a circle on the floor.
我看他是神智不清了
Well, he's lost his mind.
我清楚得很
My mind is fine.
确实有方法打败他  就是这个
And there <i>is</i> a way to beat him... With this!
世界上最莫名其妙的跳房子
The world's most confusing game of hopscotch?
不  这是个预言
No, a prophecy.
虽然用它跳房子应该也很有趣啦
Although it would be a pretty fun game of hopscotch.
多年以前  我在一个洞穴里找到了十个符号
<i>Many years ago, I found ten symbols in a cave.</i>
有些我当时就明白了  有些现在才懂
<i>Some I recognized then. Some I only recognize now.</i>
重力泉的原住民
<i>The native people of Gravity Falls</i>
预言了这些符号
<i>prophesized that these symbols</i>
可以创造出一种强大的力量  这力量足以战胜比尔
<i>could create a force strong enough to vanquish Bill.</i>
一旦比尔被击败
<i>With Bill defeated,</i>
他的怪诞世界将被推翻  小镇也能因此得救
<i>his weirdness would be reversed and the town could be saved.</i>
一直以来我都认为这只是迷信
This whole time I thought it was just superstition.
但是现在在这里看见了你们
But seeing you all here now
我终于明白了这其实是宿命
I finally understand that it's destiny!
迪普  你是松树
Dipper, the pine tree.
梅宝  流星
Mabel, the shooting star.
问号
The question mark.
这个好费解啊
This one's unsolvable.
这个简单
That one's easy.
你从初二开始就一直穿着这件蠢连帽衫了
You've been rockin' that dumb hoodie since the seventh grade.
命中注定的连帽衫
Whoa. Destiny hoodie!
心灵感应的标志
The tent of telepathy sign!
这一定是吉迪恩
That must be Gideon.
站在梅宝身边的绝佳借口
Whoo! An excuse to stand next to Mabel!
你可别想太多
Don't turn this into a big deal.
哦  我不会的
Oh, I won't.
我当然会
I <i>will.</i>
怎么
<i>What the...</i>
嘿  有破绽
<i>Hey, Achilles!</i>
先搞定脚
<i>Nice work with the heel!</i>
开球
<i>Fore!</i>
大家牵起手
Hold hands, everyone!
这是一个神秘人体能量环
This is a mystical human energy circuit.
冰  谁是冰
Ice? Who's Ice?
这些符号不止代表字面意思  迪普
They symbol's needn't all be literal, Dipper.
只需要是某个面对危险很冷静的人
It just has to be someone cool in the face of danger.
温蒂  温蒂
Wendy! Wendy!
闭嘴吧  你们
Shut up, you guys.
比如眼镜代表着一个很学术的人
Much like the spectacles need to be someone scholarly.
真是诡异
This is freaky.
现在牵起手吧  大伙儿
Now hold hands, everyone.
真恶心  我才不要碰他
Ew! I'm not touching that.
照做吧  宝贝
Do it, sweetie.
做一件我们家的人从没做过的事
Do the one thing no one in our family has ever done...
碰一个土包子
Touch the hillbilly.
阿福叔公  好像起作用了
Great-uncle Ford, I think it's working!
是的  就是这样
Yes, this is it!
剩下的人都出去  太危险了
The rest of you get out! It's too dangerous!
还需要最后一个人
We just need one more person...
斯坦利  斯坦利  快过来
Stanley! Stanley, get over here!
只剩下你了
You're the only one left.
你知道这都是胡说八道的对吧
You realize this is a bunch of hogwash, right?
难道你真的相信什么穴居人乱涂乱画的东西
You really think some caveman graffiti
可以阻止那个怪物
is gonna stop that monster?
该死  老头子  现在可不是吵架的时候
Dang it, old man, now's not the time!
-快点  -你在干什么呀
- Come on! - What are you doing?
你会毁了这一切的
You're gonna ruin this!
我从来没和人握过这么久的手  现在超不爽
I've never held hands this long, and I <i>very</i> uncomfortable!
我可不是这里的罪魁祸首  各位
Whoa. Hey, I'm not the enemy here, people.
别忘了世界末日事实上是谁创造出来的
Don't forget who literally created the end of the world.
抱歉  斯坦利  我明白
I'm sorry, Stanley. I know.
但请帮我解决这一切  拜托了
Just help me fix it! Please!
好吧  只需要你做一件事
Fine. Just do one thing.
说“谢谢”
Say "thank you."
-什么  -我花了三十年
- What? - I spent thirty years
努力把你拉回这个时空
trying to bring you back into this dimension,
你还没有谢过我
and you still haven't thanked me!
你想跟我握手
You want me to shake your hand?
先对我说“谢谢”
Say "thank you"!
好吧  谢谢
Fine. Thank you.
现在知道了吧
Now, see?
在我他之间  我也不总是那个坏兄弟
Between me and him, I'm not always the bad twin.
是“我们之间”
Between "him and me."
注意语法  斯坦利
Grammar, Stanley.
“注意语法  斯坦利” 你个混蛋自大狂
I'll "Grammar, Stanley" <i>you,</i> you stuck-up son-of-a...
大家还很危险  你个笨蛋
Don't jeopardize this, you idiot!
-现在是千钧一发的时刻  -快住手
- Everything's on the line! - Stop it!
快拉手
Join hands!
哦  不  比尔来了
<i>Oh, no, it's Bill!</i>
对吧  你们脑子里是不是正在想这句话
<i>Right? Isn't that what you're all thinking?</i>
吉迪恩  你怎么不跳舞了
<i>Hey, Gideon, why aren't you dancing?</i>
赶紧的哦
<i>Chop chop, huh?</i>
这一切简直太完美了
<i>This is just too perfect!</i>
你们这些天才不知道十二宫图只有在
<i>Didn't you brainiacs know the zodiac doesn't work</i>
所有人拉起手来的时候才生效吗
<i>if you don't all hold hands?</i>
更完美的是
<i>And what's better,</i>
你们把所有能威胁到我的力量
<i>you've brought every threat to my power together</i>
全集中在了一个能轻易摧毁的小圈子里
<i>in one easy-to-destroy circle!</i>
哦  不
Oh, no!
我的头发
Aaah! My hair!
还有我的头发
Aaah! My hair also!
你们俩想看看当你们兄弟不合时
<i>You guys want to see what happens to your friends</i>
会让朋友们遭遇什么吗
<i>when you can't get along?</i>
把他们放了
Hey! You give them back!
你太过分了  赛弗
You've gone too far, Cipher!
对  我们不怕你
Yeah! We're not scared of you!
但是你们应该怕我的
<i>Oh, but you should be.</i>
哦  不
Oh, no!
要知道  这个城堡现在正缺一些装饰品呢
<i>Ya know, this castle could really use some decoration!</i>
看来你的朋友已经没救了  斯坦福
<i>Looks like it's too late for your friends, Stanford!</i>
孩子们
Kids!
但你仍然可以挽救你的家人
<i>But you can still save your family!</i>
最后一个机会  告诉我怎样让湮灭之日散播到全世界
<i>Last chance: Tell me how to take Weirdmageddon global</i>
我就会放了孩子们
<i>and I'll spare the kids!</i>
-不  别这么做  -对
- No! Don't do it! - Yeah!
比尔会毁约的
Bill makes bad deals!
别想耍我  流星
<i>Don't you toy with me, shooting star!</i>
我能看见一切
<i>I see everything!</i>
不是吧  又来
<i>Ow! Not again!</i>
为什么每次都这样
<i>Why?! Every time!</i>
干得好  宝贝
Nice shot, pumpkin!
我刚让这只眼再生出来
<i>I just regenerated that eye!</i>
我就知道那很疼
I <i>know</i> that hurts,
因为我不小心在我自己身上试验过
because I've accidentally done it to myself...
好几次呢
Multiple times!
你们多保重
Save yourselves!
快跑  比尔交给我们
Run! We'll take care of Bill!
-什么  -这无异于自杀
- What?! - That's a suicide mission!
相信我们  我们以前能打败他
Trust us. We've beat him before...
现在也不在话下
and we'll beat him again!
比尔  来抓我们啊
Hey, Bill! Come and get us,
你个尖角笨蛋
you pointy jerk!
-什么  -不行  太危险了
- What? - No! It's too dangerous!
别急着走  你俩就在这儿等着吧
<i>Not so fast! You two wait here!</i>
我现在要去干掉几个小孩子
<i>I've got some children I need to make into corpses!</i>
咱们待会儿见
<i>See ya real soon!</i>
比尔  不要
Bill, no!
我们该怎么办  我们该怎么办
What do we do? What do we do?
孩子们
Kids!
一旦我抓住你们两个小鬼
<i>When I get my hands on you kids,</i>
我就把你们拆解成分子
<i>I'm gonna disassemble your molecules!</i>
这是你们最后一次对我耍花招了
<i>You've tricked me for the last time!</i>
真不敢相信
Ohh! I can't <i>believe</i> this!
孩子们要死了  这全都是我的错
The kids are gonna die, and it's all my fault...
因为我不肯握你那愚蠢的手
Because I couldn't shake your stupid hand!
老爸说得对  我就是个败家子
Ahh, Dad was right about me. I <i>am</i> a screw-up.
别自责了
Ah, don't blame yourself.
我才是最初跟比尔签订协议的人
I'm the one who made a deal with Bill in the first place.
我被他的花言巧语冲昏了头脑
I fell for all his easy flattery.
你真该看看他是怎样一个骗子大师
You would have seen him for the scam artist he is.
我们之间怎么变得一团糟了
How did things get so messed up between us?
我们以前跟迪普和梅宝一样
We used to be like Dipper and Mabel.
即使面对世界末日  仍然一起奋斗
The world's about to end and they still work together.
他们怎么办到的
How do they do it?
简单  他们年纪小
Easy. They're kids.
还不了解什么
They don't know any better.
你要去哪里
Whoa, where you goin'?
我要打出我们最后一张底牌了
I'm gonna play the only card we have left.
让比尔进入我的思维
Let Bill into my mind.
他就可以掌控银河系
He'll be able to take over the galaxy,
甚至更糟
and maybe even worse,
但至少他可能会放过那些孩子
but at least he <i>might</i> let the kids free.
什么  有没有搞错
What?! Are you kiddin' me?!
我们除了这个真的什么都做不了吗
Are you honestly telling me there's nothing else we can do?!
比尔只有在思维空间才有弱点
Bill's only weak in the mind space.
如果我的脑袋里没有这块可恶的金属板
If I didn't have this darn plate in my head,
当他进入我的精神世界时
we could just erase him with the memory gun
我们就可以用记忆枪消除他
when he steps inside my mind.
那要是让他进入我的精神世界呢
What if he goes into <i>my</i> mind?
我的脑子里可什么都没有
My brain isn't good for anything.
你的脑子里面没有他想要的  只能是我
There's nothing in your mind he wants. It <i>has</i> to be me.
我们必须接受他的交易
We need to take his deal.
这是让他放了你和孩子们的唯一方法
It's the only way he'll agree to save you and the kids.
你真觉得他会公平交易吗
Do you really think he's gonna make good on that deal?
我们还有其他的选择吗
What other choice do we have?
我发现这好像是一条死路
I'm starting to think there's no way out of here.
斯坦叔公经常说
Like Grunkle Stan always says,
当一扇门关闭的时候
when one door closes,
选择离你最近的一堵墙
choose a nearby wall and bash it in
用最大的力气打碎它
with brute force!
我们现在把镇民集合起来
Ha! Now let's round up the townsfolk,
团结一致  就能战胜
and together we can defeat...
哦  不
Oh, no!
怪兽们  只要我们还活着  就绝不认输
You'll never take us alive, monsters!
我们无所谓啊
That's fine with us!
-哦 不  -躲猫猫
- Oh, no! <i>- Peek-a-boo!</i>
好了  斯坦福  时间到
<i>All right, Ford, time's up!</i>
我抓住小鬼了
<i>I've got the kids!</i>
现在我打算把他们之中的一个杀掉
<i>I think I'm gonna kill one of 'em now,</i>
只是因为我想玩玩
<i>just for the heck of it!</i>
不是别人
<i>Eeenie-meenie...</i>
就是
<i>minee...</i>
等等
Wait!
我投降
I surrender!
明智的选择
Good choice.
别这样  阿福  他会摧毁全宇宙
Don't do it, Ford! It'll destroy the universe!
这是唯一的办法
It's the only way!
就算死到临头了
<i>Even when you're about to die,</i>
你们这对双胞胎也不能好好相处
<i>you Pines twins just can't get along!</i>
我唯一的条件就是你放过我兄弟和这些孩子们
My only condition is that you let my brother and the kids go.
好吧
<i>Fine.</i>
不要  阿福叔公  不要相信他
No, Grunkle Ford! Don't trust him!
就这么  定了
<i>It's a... deal!</i>
我来了  我终于来了
<i>Oh, I'm here. I'm finally here!</i>
看看这地方  多么完美祥和  井然有序的空白
<i>Look at this place... a perfect, calm, orderly void.</i>
真是佩服你  阿福
<i>Gotta hand it to you, Ford,</i>
你还真有两下子  清理得这么
<i>you really know how to clear your...</i>
什么
<i>What?!</i>
哈哈  我扮演我兄弟
Ha ha! Do a pretty good impression
演得不错吧
of my brother, don't I?
只要换下衣服  没有人能够分清我们两个
Switch clothes and no one can tell us apart.
欢迎进入我的精神世界  你竟然没有发觉
Welcome to my mind. Surprised you didn't recognize it.
斯坦利・派恩斯
什么  交易取消
<i>What?! The deal's off!</i>
怎么回事  不不不
<i>What the... No, no, no, no!</i>
没错  你完蛋了  比尔
Oh, yeah. You're goin' down, Bill.
你要被消除了
You're gettin' erased.
记忆消除枪  很聪明的点子吧
Memory gun. Pretty clever, huh?
你个傻瓜  你难道没发觉
<i>Y-You idiot! Don't you realize</i>
你会将自己的思维一同毁掉吗
<i>you're destroying your own mind too?</i>
反正我也没怎么用过这个地方
Eh. It's not like I was using this space for much anyway.
让我出去  快让我
<i>Let me out of here! Let me...</i>
为什么不管用了
<i>Oh... Why isn't this working?!</i>
嘿  看着我  转过身来看着我
Hey, look at me. Turn around and look at me,
你这个一只眼的魔鬼
you one-eyed demon!
你的确是个聪明的家伙
You're a real wiseguy,
但是你犯了一个致命的错误
but you made one fatal mistake.
你惹毛了我一家
You messed with my family.
你正在铸下弥天大错
You're <i>making a mistake!</i>
我可以给你任何回报  金钱  名望  荣华富贵
<i>I'll give you anything... Money, fame, riches,</i>
无穷的力量  甚至是你的整个星系
<i>infinite power, your own galaxy!</i>
求你了  不要
<i>Please! No!</i>
我这是怎么了
<i>What's happening to me?!</i>
斯坦利
<i>Staaanleeey!</i>
大概到头来我也不是完全一无是处
Heh. Guess I was good for something after all.
我的天哪
Oh, my gosh!
斯坦叔公  你做到了
Grunkle Stan, you did it!
你好啊  小朋友
Oh, uh, hey there... kiddo.
你叫什么
What's your name?
斯坦叔公
Grunkle Stan?
你在和谁说话呢
Heh. Who ya talkin' to?
拜托了  是我啊
C-Come on. It's <i>me.</i>
是我啊  斯坦叔公
It's me, Grunkle Stan!
斯坦叔公  是我啊
Grunkle Stan, it's me!
为了打败比尔  我们消除了他的记忆
We had to erase his mind to defeat Bill.
一切都烟消云散了
It's all gone.
斯坦他现在什么都不知道  但是他成功了
Stan has no idea, but he did it.
他拯救了世界
He saved the world.
也拯救了我
He saved me.
你是我们的英雄  斯坦利
You're our hero, Stanley.
嘿  这真是个不错的地方
Hey, this is a real nice place ya got here.
这是你的家  斯坦叔公
It's <i>your</i> place, Grunkle Stan.
你都不记得了吗  哪怕一丁点也好
Don't you remember? Even a little?
不记得了  但是这把椅子像是有记忆一样环抱着我的屁股
Nope, but this chair hugs my butt like it remembers.
嘿  为什么拉长着脸
Hey, why the long faces?
你们看上去像是出席谁的葬礼
You guys look like it's someone's funeral.
在角落里哭泣的大家伙是谁啊
Who's that big guy crying in the corner?
我们是拯救了世界  可是意义何在
We saved the world, but what's the point?
斯坦叔公再也不是那个斯坦叔公了
Grunkle Stan's not himself anymore.
一定有办法唤回他的记忆的
There's gotta be something we can do to jog his memory!
真的没有  很遗憾  斯坦已经不在了
There isn't. I'm sorry. Stan's gone.
我知道我的叔公一定还留在某个地方
I <i>know</i> my Grunkle is in there somewhere!
这里一定有什么东西
There's gotta be something around here
可以帮我们带他回来
that can help bring him back!
夏日回忆
这个会有用  这个一定会有用
This'll work! This has to work!
斯坦叔公  这是我们来重力泉的第一天
Here's the first day we came to Gravity Falls, Grunkle Stan.
这是我用意大利通心粉表述的心情
And here's a macaroni interpretation of my emotions.
那次我们一起去钓鱼
That time we went fishing.
那是我们一起度过暑圣节
That Summerween we spent together.
你一点都不记得了吗
Don't you remember anything?
对不起  我不知道这都是什么
I'm sorry. I don't know what this is
也不知道你们是谁 啊
or who you are or... gah!
不要这样  摇摇
Quit it, Waddles!
我在努力回忆我的一生
I'm trying to remember my life story!
你刚才说什么
What did you say?
我让摇摇离我远点
I said get Waddles off of me!
起效了  接着读
It's working! Keep reading!
跳到我那一页
Skip to my page!
他需要回忆起我们的雇佣关系
He needs to remember our boss-employee relationship.
嘿  不要以为我得了失忆症
Hey! Just cause I have amnesia,
你就可以给自己升职了  苏斯
don't go tryin' to give yourself a raise, Soos.
真的起效了  快接着来
It's happening! Keep going!
好的好的
OK. OK!
第二天  斯坦叔公闻起来怪怪的
"Day Two. Grunkle Stan smells weird
但是我们渐渐亲密起来
but we're starting to bond.
他和我们讲了好多在八十年代从商的经历
He told us a lot about being a businessman in the '80s
我们装作在听  他似乎很高兴
and seemed happy when we pretended to listen.
他还给了我一个
He also gave me a grappling hook
威震全场的爪勾
which everyone is impressed by.
还有些更重要的消息
And in more important news,
我遇到了几个邻家的帅哥
I've met some neighborhood hotties!"
早安  重力泉
<i>Good Morning, Gravity Falls!</i>
又是美妙的一天  不过每天都是如此美妙
<i>It's another beautiful day, but every day is beautiful</i>
现在  不愉快的事情已经过去
<i>now that the... unpleasantness is over.</i>
滚出去  你们这群古怪的生物
Git outta here, ya ornery critters!
啊  焕然一新了
Ah, good as new.
看来你交了个新朋友哦
Oh! Looks like you've got a friend!
罗比乖孩子  能帮我们个忙把霰弹枪拿来吗
Robbie, would you be a dear and get us the sawed off shotgun?
呃  好吧  随便了
Ugh. Fine, whatever.
大脑什么的
Brains and so forth!
不  什么都没有  谢谢
Nope! None of that, thank you.
我们没有人真正清楚到底发生了什么
None of us really understand what just happened,
也没有人想去弄明白
and none of us want to.
为此我通过了“什么都别在意”法案
That's why I'm passing the Never Mind All That Act.
如果谁要谈论过去几天发生的“事件”
If anyone goes asking around about the "events" of the last few days,
我们要怎么说呢
what do we say?
什么都别在意
Never Mind All That!
如果你破了戒  我们就要电倒你
And if you break the rules, we're gonna zap ya!
电  电
Zap! Zap!
我们被力量冲昏了头脑
We're mad with power!
还有爱
And love.
另一则新闻
<i>In other news,</i>
诺斯韦斯特一家已经破产
<i>the Northwest family has gone broke.</i>
出售
为了向比尔表示忠诚
<i>After pledging his allegiance to Bill</i>
他把所有财产都投入怪诞债券中打了水漂
<i>and then placing all his savings in weirdness bonds,</i>
普雷斯顿・诺斯韦斯特只能卖掉他的宅邸
<i>Preston Northwest had to sell his mansion</i>
来维持他一家的生计
<i>to preserve his family fortune.</i>
你现在只能留下一匹小马了
You're only going to have one pony now!
但本地疯子费多福・麦戈科特却时来运转
But fortunes have also turned for local maniac Fiddleford McGucket
恢复神智的他
who, after regaining his sanity,
通过向美国政府申请专利
has made millions overnight submitting his patents
便一夜暴富
to the US government.
费多福・麦戈科特
我要给自己买个大点的棚子
I'm gonna buy me a bigger shed!
嘿  那一栋正在出售
Hey, that one's for sale!
另一个好消息是  小镇英雄斯坦利・派恩斯
In other good news, town hero Stanley Pines
终于完全恢复记忆并要举办一个派对
has fully recovered his memory and will be throwing a party
来庆祝他侄孙女和侄孙的十三岁生日
to celebrate his niece and nephew's thirteenth birthday
和留在小镇的最后一天
and final day in town.
再见  英雄们
除此之外  我可以确定地说
But other than that, I can safely say
我们可爱的重力泉已经恢复如初
our beloved Gravity Falls is back to normal.
现在  转给非凡之T  为您报道体育新闻
And now, Bodacious T, with sports.
这是死亡之球
It's called Death Ball!
快乐
...to you
不敢相信你们居然一起为我们举办了一个派对
I can't believe you all got together just to throw a party for us!
派恩斯一家为小镇付出了这么多
After all the Pines family has done for the town,
这是我们最起码能做的一点事
it's the least we could do!
你们帮助了这里的每个人
You've helped everyone here.
谢谢你们拯救了我们
Thanks to y'all savin' us,
我学会了敞开心胸对待善意
I learned to open my heart to kindness.
不再做坏事了
No more evil-doin'.
从现在起  我要成为小吉迪恩
From now on, I'm gonna try to be Li'l Gideon,
一个普通的小孩
regular ol' kid.
我在滑板上迈出了破纪录的一步
I am bustin' a move on this skatin' board.
还是提好你的裤子吧  废物
More like busting your pants, loser!
伙计们  许个愿吧
Dude, make a wish, dawg!
你们知道吗  我第一天来的时候
Ya know, on my first day here,
要是有人问我想要什么的时候  我可能会说
if you had asked me what I wanted, I would have said
冒险  神秘事物  真心朋友
adventure, mystery, true friends.
但是现在看着你们
But looking here at all of you,
我才发现这些愿望都已经实现了
I realize that every wish came true...
我想要的一切都得到了
I have everything I wanted.
要是只能许一个愿的话
If I had only one wish,
我想用缩小射线把你们都缩小
it would be to shrink all of you with a shrink ray
然后把你们打包带回家
and bring you home with us in my pocket.
但既然这样行不通
But since that's impossible...
真的行不通吗
<i>Is</i> that impossible?
既然这样可能行不通
Since that's <i>probably</i> impossible,
我的愿望就是让所有人都在我的剪贴簿上签名
my only wish is for everyone to sign my scrapbook.
我不会忘记你们的
I'll never forget you guys.
等等
Wait.
这下我就不会忘记你们了
<i>Now</i> I'll never forget you guys!
现在正式宣布你们算是真正的青少年了
I now officially declare you: technically teenagers.
欢迎你们加入烦心事和青春痘的阵营
Welcome to Angst and Acne Forever.
新成员  新成员
One of us! One of us!
你们感觉怎么样
So how do you feel?
还是老样子  但又有所不同
Samey, but differenty.
嘿  你们俩
Hey, you two.
你们打算什么时候拆礼物啊
When are you gonna open your presents already?
我包装的时候弄断了一个指甲呢
I broke a nail wrapping them.
哈哈  帕西菲卡
Ha ha! Pacifica.
斯坦利  我想找你谈谈
Stanley, I need to talk to you.
我不想让别人听到我说这话
I didn't want to say anything with everyone listening,
但是咱们有麻烦了
but we've got a problem.
虽然湮灭之日的事已经被控制住了
Weirdmageddon has been contained,
但是我又检测到了一些其他的反常现象
but I'm detecting some strange new anomalies
就在北冰洋附近
near the Arctic Ocean.
我倒是很想去调查一下
I want to go investigate it,
可是我觉得自己可能有点过了独自出海的年纪了
but I think I might be too old to go it alone.
你是说你缺个帮手吗
Are you sayin' you need someone to help you
一起环游世界  来场此生难忘的冒险
sail around the world on the adventure of a lifetime?
我可不是想随随便便找个人  斯坦利
I don't just want <i>someone</i> to come with me, Stanley.
我只想和你一起去
I want it to be you.
你愿意再给我一次机会吗
Will you give me a second chance?
你觉得咱们能一起去寻宝  泡妹子吗
You think we'll find treasure? And babes?
哈  要我说的话可能性很大哦
Ha! I'd say there's a high probability!
但是咱们怎么处理神秘小屋呢
But what should we do with the Mystery Shack?
我觉得这个镇子上已经经历了一场终身难忘的神秘事件了
I think the town's had enough mystery for one lifetime.
你跟我想的一样吗
Are you thinkin' what I'm thinkin'?
大家注意啦
Everyone,
我有事情要宣布
I have an announcement to make.
我和我的  这位书呆子兄弟
Me and my... heh!... Nerdy bro over here
要好好叙叙旧  可能会离开一段时间
have some catchin' up to do, we're gonna be away for a while.
所以说神秘小屋要关门大吉了
That's why I'm shutting down the Mystery Shack for good!
先让你的嘴关门大吉吧
You shut down your <i>mouth</i> for good!
抱歉  二位派恩斯先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Pineses,
但是这小屋是世界上最有魔力的地方了
it's just that this shack is the most magical place on earth.
虽说这些景点都是骗人的
Sure, the attractions are all fake,
但是梦想是最真实的
but <i>dreams</i> aren't fake.
就好比这个美人鱼
Like this mermaid:
这不只是一个缝到死猴子身上的死鱼尾巴
It's not just a dead fish butt sewn to a monkey carcass,
而是一个美妙无比的神奇生物
it's a marvelous creature
它能让我们相信一切皆有可能
that makes us believe that anything is possible.
你要是把小屋关掉的话  就等于毁灭了我们的梦想
You shut down this shack, and you shut down our dreams!
至少是我的梦想
At least... <i>my</i> dreams.
抱歉  苏斯
I'm sorry, Soos,
只是没有人能经营它了
it's just there's no one around to run it.
原本是这样的情况
At least there <i>wouldn't</i> be
还好我刚刚找到了合适的继承人
if I hadn't just found the perfect replacement.
女士们先生们  神秘小屋换了新经理
Ladies and gentlemen, the Mystery Shack is under new management!
你是认真的吗  神秘先生
You... you mean it, Mister Mystery?
现在你是神秘先生了  苏斯
You're Mister Mystery now, Soos.
小心点别把屋子烧了
Try not to burn the place down.
我马上就搬进来住
I'll move in immediately.
你非走不可吗
Do you <i>really</i> have to go?
咱们还有好多事没有一起做呢
There is still so much we haven't done together.
暑假总会结束的  糖糖
Summer's over, Candy.
该长大了
It's time for us to grow up.
但也别长太大了
But not <i>too</i> much.
啊  我好讨厌这种心塞塞的感觉
Aaah! I hate my dumb heart for making me feel things!
别闹了  小心脏
Cut. It. Out. Heart!
嘿  你能也在我心上打两拳吗
Hey, can you punch my heart too?
不  先打我吧  让我别这样多愁善感了
No, mine! Punch <i>my</i> feelings away!
糖糖  格兰达
Candy and Grenda,
谢谢你们跟我做朋友
thank you for being my people.
你们是我永远的好闺蜜
You'll always be my best friends.
斯坦叔公  谢谢你穿上我织的告别毛衣
Grunkle Stan, thanks for wearing my Goodbye sweater.
外面冷  我不得不穿啊
Ah, it's cold out. I had to.
什么  但是今天外面将近三十度呢
What? But it's, like, eighty-something degrees out today.
闭嘴  苏斯
Can it, Soos!
嘿  你在我心中可重要呢  伙计
Hey. You mean a lot to me, man.
你也是
You too.
就拿这个纪念我吧
Something to remember me by.
哦  还有这个
Oh, and this.
等下次你想念重力泉的时候就打开看吧
Read it the next time you miss Gravity Falls.
最后一班离开重力泉的大巴车了
Last bus leaving Gravity Falls.
上车
All aboard.
我已经跟所有人都告别了  除了
Guess we said goodbye to everyone except...
摇摇
Waddles.
我不知道怎么跟你说  但是
I...don't know how to explain this, but...
爸妈绝对不会让我在加利福尼亚的家里养猪的  所以
Mom and Dad won't let me bring a pig home to California, so...
你得留在这里
you have to stay here!
别这样  别这样
Come on, come on!
我得走了
I have to <i>go.</i>
我真的很抱歉  摇摇
I'm... I'm sorry, Waddles!
算了  就这样吧
You know what? Forget it!
我已经忍了这猪一整个夏天了
I lived with this pig all summer,
不管你父母想不想要它都得要
now <i>your</i> parents are gonna have to!
嘿  开车的
Hey, bus guy!
这只猪要和孩子们一起走
This pig is coming with the kids!
等一下
Now, hold on a second.
在交通工具上携带动物的行为
Bringing animals aboard a moving vehicle
是严格禁止的
is strictly prohibited by...
呃  欢迎上车
Wah... Welcome aboard.
你可以坐在第一排  小猪猪
You can sit in the front row, pig.
孩子们  你们这俩小笨蛋净给我惹麻烦
Kids, you knuckleheads were nothin' but a nuisance
总算摆脱你们了
and I'm glad to be rid of ya.
我们也会想你的  斯坦叔公
We'll miss you too, Grunkle Stan.
准备好探索未知世界了吗
Ready to head into the unknown?
没
Nope.
我们走吧
Let's do it.
加利福尼亚
大家再见  我也会想你们的
Bye! Bye, everybody! I'll miss you guys too!
再见  伙计们  再见
Bye, dudes! Bye!
如果你开车旅行经过美国西北部
<i>If you've ever taken a road trip through the Pacific Northwest,</i>
你可能会看到某张保险杠贴纸
<i>you've probably seen a bumper sticker</i>
上面标着一个叫做重力泉的地方
<i>for a place called Gravity Falls.</i>
好了  我搬进来了
Well, I've moved in.
地图上找不到它
<i>It's not on any maps,</i>
大多数人可能从未听说过它
<i>and most people have never heard of it.</i>
有些人觉得它是个传说
<i>Some people think it's a myth.</i>
全新开业
但是如果你感到好奇  别犹豫
<i>But if you're curious, don't wait.</i>
创建者
马上行动
<i>Take a trip.</i>
去找它
<i>Find it.</i>
大兵斯坦二号
它就在森林里的某处  等着你的到来
<i>It's out there somewhere in the woods.. waiting.</i>
致迪普
明年暑假见
■
全剧终  更多精彩动画请关注
迪幻字幕组  www.Deefun.com